<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="ext_input_device_calibration_unstable_v1">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2024 Holusion SAS

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <description summary="Protocol to handle input devices dynamic calibration">
    This protocol allows dynamic calibration of input devices by the clients.

    Typically absolute input devices (such as touchscreens) need to be mapped
    to once specific output in case of multiple outputs setups. However the 
    compositor may not have enough information to do this mapping. This protocol
    allows client to make this decision using external knowledge.

    Warning! The protocol described in this file is experimental and
    backward incompatible changes may be made. Backward compatible
    changes may be added together with the corresponding interface
    version bump.
  </description>

  <interface name="ext_input_calibration_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="manage input devices calibration">
      A global factory interface for input_device objects.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the ext_input_calibration_manager object">
	      Using this request a client can tell the server that it is not
	      going to use the object anymore.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="add">
      <description summary="new input device">
        This event is sent when a new input device is added
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="ext_input_device_v1"
        summary="the new input device"/>
    </event>

    <event name="done">
      <description summary="sent all information about active inputs">
        This event is sent after all information has been sent after binding to
        the output manager object and after any subsequent changes. This applies
        to child devices as well. In other words, this event is sent whenever a
        head or mode is created or destroyed and whenever one of their properties
        has been changed. Not all state is re-sent each time the current
        configuration changes: only the actual changes are sent.

        This allows changes to the input configuration to be seen as atomic,
        even if they happen via multiple events.

      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>

  <interface name="ext_input_device_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="compositor input device">
      An ext_input_device object represents an input device in the compositor.
    </description>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="no_such_output" value="1"
        summary="requested output name was not found"/>
      <entry name="bad_boundaries" value="2"
        summary="could not match the requested boundaries"/>
      <entry name="already_used" value="3"
        summary="request sent after configuration has been applied or tested"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="types">
      <entry name="keyboard" value="0" summary="keyboard device"/>
      <entry name="pointer" value="1" summary="pointer (typ. mouse) device"/>
      <entry name="touch" value="2" summary="touchscreen / trackpad device"/>
      <entry name="tablet_tool" value="3" summary="tablet tool device"/>
      <entry name="tablet_pad" value="4" summary="tablet pad device"/>
      <entry name="switch" value="5" summary="switch device"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="release" type="destructor">
      <description summary="release the ext_input_device object">
        Using this request a client can tell the server that it is not
        going to use the object anymore.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="map_to_region">
      <description summary="map the input device to a box">
        Asks the compositor to map the input device's absolute coordinates to a
        rectangle in output space
      </description>
      <arg name="width" type="int" summary="width in pixels of the box"/>
      <arg name="height" type="int" summary="width in pixels of the box"/>
      <arg name="x" type="int" summary="x position of the box"/>
      <arg name="y" type="int" summary="y position of the box"/>
    </request>

    <request name="map_to_output">
      <description summary="map the input device to an output device">
        Asks the compositor to map the input device's absolute coordinates to an
        output device's on-screen position.

        The output name should be the value reported by xdg_output.name and zwlr_output_head_v1.name
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="string" summary="output name to map to"/>
    </request>

    <event name="removed">
      <description summary="input device removed">
        This event is sent when the input device is removed
        Clients should release it.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="name">
      <description summary="The input device's name">
        An input device will generally have a manufacturer's defined name
        describing the device. This event provides that name.
      </description>
      <arg name="name" type="string" summary="input name"/>
    </event>

    <event name="vendor">
      <description summary="The input device's vendor">
        An input device will have a vendor, as in "USB Bus vendor ID".
      </description>
      <arg name="vendor" type="uint" summary="input vendor"/>
    </event>

    <event name="product">
      <description summary="The input device product identifier">
        An input device will have a USB Bus product ID.
      </description>
      <arg name="vendor" type="uint" summary="input product"/>
    </event>

    <event name="type">
      <description summary="The input device's type">
        An input device will have a type, such as "touch" or "pointer"
      </description>
      <arg name="type" type="int" enum="ext_input_device_v1.types" summary="input type"/>
    </event>
    <!-- Add other device properties -->
    
  </interface>
</protocol>
